Victor Alan Hernandez Muñoz

Chetumal, Quintana Roo | HMvictoralan@gmail.com

Profile

I am a qualified and professional Data Analyst with a solid understanding of mathematics, physics, statistics and programming with experience in database administration and dashboards design. I am dedicated to helping organizations make informed decisions based on data driven evidence. Extracting, cleaning and analyzing visual information within "stories" in the data is what I use to communicate solutions.

Education

Centro de Investigación en Ingeniería y Ciencias Aplicadas (CIICAp)

Bachelor of Licenciatura en Tecnología (Física aplicada) | 2013 - 2017

Ironhack

Data Analytics Bootcamp | Oct. 21 - Mar. 22

Professional Experience

DISKO KITTIEZ | WEB SCRAPER | DATA ANALYST JR (Intern) | Aug 2021 - May 2022

- Execute day-to-day social media scraping using selenium/python to gather users (Music Artists) information from social media accounts (Instagram, facebook, twitter, youtube)
- Design dashboards (Tableau, Streamlit) of user information for artist outreach for music collaboration within the platform.

CRYPTOSTACKERS | MARKET RESEARCH ANALYST (Intern) | Aug 2021 - May2022

- Research and analyze crypto-coins updates to give insights to traders and their teams on recent developments that may impact their portfolios in the crypto markets.
- Gather data from various sources, including blockchain explorers, exchanges, social media, and industry reports and evaluate the potential value and long-term prospects of cryptocurrencies, tokens, and blockchain projects.

Agroalimentos Negocios Inteligentes | BackEnd | 2019 Sep - Jul 2021

- Creation and maintenance of the MySql server for Micro Farms while promoting cooperative projects in the countryside of Mexico.
- Analyzing prices and competition of customers in their development. Handled imports and distribution of coffee, mango and rambutan.

Ingeniería Aplicada Arduino | Meta Designer | Arduino Programmer 2017 Sep - Aug 2019

- Worked on creating, coding and designing an all-in-one Cnc, 3D printer, Laser Engraver.
- Designed base for DHT11 Digital Temperature Humidity Sensor.
- Flashing MicroPython to Arduino one for Automation Use on Robots.
- Designed Multiple 3D Components for Arduino Bots.

Courses and Certifications

- OpenAI Python API Bootcamp: Learn to use AI, GPT | Jul. 2023
- Java Polimorfismo: Entendiendo herencia e interfaces | May 2023
- Sql con MySql Server de Oracle One | Aug. 2023
- Git y GitHub: controle y comparta su código | April. 2022
- Building Machine Learning Web Apps with Python | Jun. 2022
- My TOEFL iBT® Test Score: 92 | May 2022

Skills

- Data Analysis using Python (Pandas, NumPy) & MySQL.
- Build, Evaluate & Deploy Machine Learning Models and Pipelines (Scikit-Learn).
- Inferential Statistics in Python & Business Intelligence.
- Deep Learning, Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Cleaning, ETL.
- Data Wrangling, Data Cleaning, API.
- Web Scraping (Selenium).
- Tensorflow (Image classification) CNN ANN.
- Data Visualization (Tableau, Streamlit (Plotly & Seaborn).
- Process improvement (Salesforce, Stakeholder management).
- Git/GitHub, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab, Pycharm.
- Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning.
- Storytelling with Data Presentation.

Projects

Python Bot: https://pythonbot.streamlit.app/

Uses the Streamlit library to create a web application. This application is designed for simplifying data analysis and programming tasks in Python. The script expresses excitement about having users on board and offering assistance through the "Nosotros" (Us) section. It also encourages users to enjoy using Python.

• **Sql Bot:** https://sqlbot.streamlit.app/

This code represents the core structure of the "Mysql Bot" web application, which provides a user interface for interacting with data stored in CSV files using natural language queries and an integrated AI model. The functionality for different views, data processing, which may be distributed across multiple files.

Image Classification with TensorFlow

This Project creates a deep learning model using TensorFlow that can analyze images of land or properties and provide insights into the type of housing and details of the property. It combines image classification and property description generation, making it a tool for real estate professionals and potential buyers. This project offers a comprehensive solution for real estate professionals and individuals seeking detailed information about properties based on images. It leverages both computer vision and natural language processing to provide valuable insights into the housing market